ラジオ英会話 ハートでつかめ 英語の極意講師の大西 博人です
金曜復習会ですね 頑張っていきましょう
Hey everyone, this is Akino Rosa. Welcome to Friday's Review.
And I'm David Evans. Alright everyone, let's get to it.
さあ それでは早速始めていきましょう
Lesson 130
今週のリビュー 金曜日は復習会です
最初のコーナーはこちら
リスニングチャレンジ
OK
Let's review this week's dialogues
Listen to the questions
and pick which one of the three options
is the correct answer
Let's start with Monday's dialogue
OK guys, here's the question
What did Megan decide to order?
A. A steak for her and chips for Anton
B. A steak for Anton and chips for her
ステーキとチップスの2つのオーディオを紹介します
では行きましょう
あなたは英国から来ていませんか?
いや、私たちは遠くから来ています
私もです。私は日本から来ています。私の名前はキンゾです
私の名前はメーガンです。お会いしましょう
では、何をオーディオにしたいですか?
何をお勧めしますか?
ステーキとチップスはとても美味しいです
sounds great i'll get one for me and one for anton here
is he your husband oh no he is a
pilot oh he doesn't look like a seaman
did you get that let's go over the question one more time
what did megan decide to order a a steak for her and chips for anton b
a steak for anton and chips for her or c two orders of steak and chips
答えは
c two orders of steak and chips
質問はメーガンは何を注文することにした
a 自分にステーキアントンにチップス
b アントンにステーキ自分にチップス
c ステーキ&チップスを2つ
答えはc
ステーキ&チップスを2つとなります
Alright, now let's move on to Tuesday's dialogue
First, here's the question
Which of the following is true?
A. Derek and Bill were invited to the talk show together
B. Derek is willing to be on the talk show
Or C. Bill doesn't like the talk show
Listen up
derek do you ever watch the kelly king show
yeah sometimes it's a talk show right why
well i just got a phone call from them they've invited you to be on the
program just me and not bill
kelly already had bill on the show before
ah yeah i saw that one sure i can do it
not so fast derek the question is whether you should accept the
invitation or not
Well, why shouldn't I?
Bill might not approve.
OK, how did you do?
Let's check out the question one more time.
Which of the following is true?
A. Derek and Bill were invited to the talk show together.
B. Derek is willing to be on the talk show.
C. Bill doesn't like the talk show.
答えは?
b デリック is willing to be on the talk show 質問は次のうち正しいのは a デレクとビルは一緒にトーク番組に招かれた
b デレクはそのトーク番組に出ることを望んでいる c ビルはそのトーク番組が好きではない
答えは b デレクはそのトーク番組に出ることを望んでいるとなります
ウェンスデイズダイアローグ
アコーディングトゥダマンインウォッセンシュリアーデイ
エイ
デイティンセンシュリ
ウォーシー
レッスンケアフリー
ユアクローザーベリーインテルスティン
アリーチューゴイントゥアコスチュームパーティ
ノー
何か質問したいんですか?
もちろんです。
何年ですか?
ああ、私の英語をテストしています。
1865年です。西洋年です。
嘘をしないでください。2024年です。
ごめんなさい、お母さん。
それは次世代以上です。
次世代とは何ですか?
20世代になるとは思っていません。
そうではありません。
I was born in the 20th century
Please, I'm getting bored with your strange humor
How'd you do?
Let's check out the question one more time
According to the man, in what century are they?
A. The 18th century
B. The 19th century
Or C. The 20th century
答えは?
B. The 19th century
質問は?
男性によると彼らは何世紀にいる a 18世紀 b 19世紀 c 20世紀
答えは b 19世紀となります ok last up is thursday's dialogue let's check out the
question how did エモリさん surprise the woman how did エモリさん surprise the woman a
彼は金閣寺のミニチュアを建てた
B.彼は彼女にゴールデンスカルプシュアを見せた
C.彼は彼女のクレデットカードを見つけた
ここに行きましょう
エモリさん!
久々に見ないよ
どうしたの?
いいよ
お見事だよ
ありがとう
エメルに言ったら
私に驚かせた
イエス プリーズ カメン サイド イッツ イン ドゥ バック ヤー ドゥ バック ヤー ドゥ バック ヤー ドゥ バック ヤー ドゥ バック ヤー ドゥ バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バック ヤー バ
It looks just like the real one, only smaller.
Alright, how did you do?
Let's check out the question one more time, okay?
How did Emori-san surprise the woman?
A. He built a miniature kinkakuji.
B. He showed a golden sculpture to her.
C. He found her credit card in the backyard.
答えは?
A.
質問は、エモリさんは女性をどのように驚かせた?
A. ミニチュアの金閣寺を作った
B. 彼女に金色の彫刻を見せた
C. 彼女のクレジットカードを裏庭で見つけた
答えはA. ミニチュアの金閣寺を作ったとなります
英語で言ってください
今週練習した表現を使って会話の実践練習をしましょう
OK Here's the first situation
Imagine this
重要なクライアントとのオンラインミーティングについて
自宅にいる部下に連絡・説明してください
例えば
ミーティングは午後3時からです
数分前にログインしてください
たとえオンラインであっても
私たちは重要な顧客と会います
言うまでもないことですが、きちんとした服装である必要がありますよ。いいですか?など。
3ヒントを差し上げておきましょう。
言うまでもないことですが、これはit goes without saying but。
そしてきちんとした服装で、これはbe dressed properlyというフレーズが使えます。
さあもう一度シチュエーションを確認しましょう。
重要なクライアントとのオンラインミーティングについて自宅にいる部下に連絡 説明してください
例えば ミーティングは午後3時からです数分前にログインしてください
たとえオンラインであっても私たちは重要な顧客と合います 言うまでもないことですがきちんとした服装である必要がありますよ
いいですかなど さあ部下にこう聞かれますよ
We have a meeting this afternoon. Right, boss?
あなたならどう言いますか?
それではここでローズさんの答えを聞きましょう
では内容を順番に確認します
b 動詞の後ろが from 3 p.m. と全知識
どんな表現を使っても b 動詞の後ろにおけば説明語句となります
even though it's online we're meeting important clients
it goes without saying but you need to be dressed properly okay
even though はたとえ何々でも
need to は何々する必要がある
それではローズさんの答えをもう一度聞きましょう
あなたはパーティーの主催者の一人
初めて来た人にパーティーの写真を送ってあげましょう
例えば
やあ楽しんでいますか名前はデイビット よろしければこのパーティーの写真を送ってあげたいのですがどうやって送ったらいいでしょう
あなたの連絡先を教えてもらえませんか など
ヒントを差し上げておきましょう 連絡先これはコンタクトインフォーと言います
もう一度シチュエーションを確認しますね あなたはパーティーの主催者の一人
初めて来た人にパーティーの写真を送ってあげましょう 例えばや楽しんでいますか名前はデイビット
よろしければこのパーティーの写真を送ってあげたいのですがどうやって送ったら いいでしょう
あなたの連絡先を教えてもらえませんか など
さあパーティーに来た女性に挨拶されますよ hi there あなたならどう言いますか
それでは、ここでデイビッドさんの答えを聞きましょう。
では、内容を順番に確認します。
Send you the photos of this partyは需要型
あなたにこのパーティーの写真を送るとなっています
How should Iに続く動詞プラス目的語プラスtoも
需要を表すことのできる形
Giveを使った需要型の文です
それではデイビッドさんの答えをもう一度聞きましょう
Hi. Having a good time?
Name's David.
If it's okay with you, I'd like to send you the photos of this party.
How should I send them to you?
Could you give me your contact info?
Hey guys. Do you dress well when you have an online meeting?
なるほど
というわけで今日はこのへんで
バイ